Ahmet OZKESEK

17 Stonor Road GFF West Kensington W14 8RZ LONDON

M: 0772 922 3112

E: <u>aozkesek@gmail.com</u>

Summary

I am 25+ years experienced Software Developer/Programmer with a Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering. I developed software for Call Contact Centre Systems, ATM Management Systems, Work-Flow and Document Management Systems. I worked in Banking and Financial sector in Istanbul for 15 years. What I am looking for is;

- A London based, contractor, either inside or outside IR35, Java Programmer role
- The role should require less FE/UI development and no CSS, AngularJS, ReactJS
- The role should require no lead, management tasks

Experience

OCT 2016 - date	Oct 2016 - date	Istanbul, London	Freelancer
-----------------	-----------------	------------------	------------

- Chose voluntarily to be unemployed and focused myself, while self studying Java EE, AWS, Document DB/NoSQL like that
- Self studied, passed exam 1Z0-809 OCP Java 8 SE Programmer II (81%) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate-ocp.pdf
- Self studied, passed exam 1Z0-808 OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I (94%) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate-oca.pdf
- Designing and developing an Android Video Chat Application https://github.com/aozkesek/p2p-cast
- Designed and developed a Hospital Management Software with Biometric Verification for ZieZix360 a Nigerian Company. It was a Proof of Concept application that contains a Fingerprint and a Camera reader service module, multiple web service modules, and a web UI module. https://github.com/aozkesek/ziezix360-hm https://ziezix360.com/about-us/
- Developed a group of PoC applications for an e-commerce web site and it's test automations https://github.com/aozkesek/alev-e-commerce https://github.com/aozkesek/selenium-json-suite-runner

Jul 2014 - Aug 2016	NETAS, Istanbul	Consultant
Jai Zori Mag Zoro	ite in s, istalled	Consultant

- Designed some services and wrote their Technical Design Document for companies that use Cisco Unified Communication and IP Desktop Phones.
- Created a prototype of IP Phone Service to join AVAYA Developer Connect Program

 $\underline{https://www.devconnectprogram.com/site/global/program_benefits/overview/index.gsp}$

https://downloads.avava.com/css/P8/documents/101026461

_

- Developed a web application for managing a group of Cisco IP Phone Services https://github.com/aozkesek/iis-app-manager

 https://github.com/aozkesek/license-manager
- Trained the junior team members

Nov 2001 - Jan 2014	Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul	Senior Programmer
---------------------	---------------------------	-------------------

- Led a Workflow Management Development team for 3 months
- Developed and maintained Workflow and Document Management software
- Developed and maintained ATM and Telephone Banking softwares
- Involved merging of Unicredit Kocbank and Yapi Kredi Bank
- Developed and maintained On-line and Telephone Banking software

Aug 1999 - Aug 2001	Demirbank, Istanbul	Programmer
---------------------	---------------------	------------

Developed and maintained Telephone Banking and Contact Centre software

Skills

- Still developing: AWS (IAM, ...), Document DB / NoSQL (Mongo, Redis, ...)
- Java 8, JavaScript
- JEE: Spring Framework & Boot, Hibernate ORM, JSF & Primefaces
- C#. C
- ASP.NET, Entity Framework, PostSharp
- TDD: Junit, TestNG, Selenium
- Docker, Docker Compose
- Gradle, Maven, Git
- JRDBMS: Oracle, MS-SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- JTAPI & Cisco, Genesys CTI & IVR

Education

University of Istanbul, 1990 – 1997, Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering (https://bilgisayarmuhendislik.istanbulc.edu.tr/en/)

Qualifications

- Pearson Vue, London, 2020: **OCP** Java 8 SE Programmer II, (1Z0-809, 81%) https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/73245c76-e69e-4d2f-9513-780e5e98aae8
- Pearson Vue, London, 2019: OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I (1Z0-808, 94%)
- Genesys, Istanbul, 2010: Certified GVP (IP IVR) Developer Course
- Cisco, Istanbul, 2007: CUCM Cisco Unified Communication Manager Course
- Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul, 2005: JSP, MVC Apache Struts Course
- Genesys, San Fransisco, 2001: Genesys Certified CTI Developer Course
- Netron, Istanbul, 1999: ASP VBScript, COM VB & C++ Course